The Princess Sapphire
Knight of the Ribbon
Atashi no miru yume himitsu nano
The dreams I see are my secret
Dare ni mo iwanai himitsu nano
I won’t tell anyone—it’s my secret
Akai manto hira hira
A red cape fluttering
Uma o tobasu oujo
Galloping on a horse—the princess
Sore ga atashi
That’s me!
Lula dula lula dula
Lulu laa, lulaa
Ribon no kishi wa
The Knight of the Ribbon,
Honto wa hontto wa
Truly, truly,
Atashi nano sa
It’s really me!
Thirty-Third Episode
The Egyptian Adventure
Here on the sea there is a lot of mist,
especially in winter!
Often we don't notice the enemy
because of the mist.
A day like today
is very dangerous,
therefore it is important
to stay well on guard!
An enemy ship!
Who knows where it comes from...
What could this possibly be?
Don't worry.
Where do you come from?
- Why are you wearing this
iron ring? - I escaped!
Please, be kind, take this
horrible iron ring off me at once!
Oh, no, I can't take it off you!
What is this mark?
This iron ring is the symbol
of the sacrifice to the deity.
Sacrifice, you said?
What sacrifice?
Every year, ten girls are
buried alive underground...
...as a sacrifice to the
deity! Thank you very much!
Buried alive?! How is
such cruelty possible?
The persecutors are coming!
- Quick, help me escape!
- Hide behind the Fort! Go!
It won't open anymore!
Which country's soldiers are you?
Girl destined for sacrifice,
why did you run away?
- You will be severely punished!
- But what are you talking about?
I am Sapphire, the
Princess of Silverland!
Shut up! You cannot deceive us
even if you have changed your clothes!
You are a girl of our country
and the iron ring is the proof!
That's enough! Take her to the ship!
- I'm tired, let me sleep!
- Come on, wake up! You lazybones!
Are you awake, beautiful girl?
Who are you? And where am I?
Are you still trying
to feign ignorance?
There is no one in the world
who doesn't know this country!
Look at that
great seaside city...
...and look at those three
great pyramids in the desert!
Great seaside city...
Pyramids..!
So, according to Dr. Uranaru,
this country is Egypt!
This is the largest city
in Egypt: Alexandria.
And I am Morufo,
the celebrant of rites.
Morufo? Listen, Morufo,
you're wrong, I am not that girl!
Do you still intend
to feign ignorance?
Don't you think it's very honorable
to be a sacrificial victim?
You were chosen
because you are beautiful!
And furthermore,
by offering sacrifices,
we can calm the wrath of Osiris
and this country will know peace.
It's nonsense! A country
cannot become peaceful...
...by offering sacrifices!
- Queen Deida wants you.
...and nine other girls
to be offered in sacrifice!
Ten girls? Damn!
The ten beautiful girls
will be offered in sacrifice..
...on the first night
of the splendid full moon!
I must manage to escape!
Absolutely!
- What is happening to you?
- This iron ring hurts!
- Please, take this ring off me!
- Well... All right!
There you go!
Damn! How dare you?
It's between the two of us now!
Halt!
Prince Amesisis?!
I am the only son of the deceased
Queen Deida: Amesisis.
I am the Princess of Silverland:
Sapphire.
Princess of Silverland?
I want to believe you!
Judging by your skill
in using the sword,
you are different from the normal girls
of this country.
Let me go, please.
What is it?
I know they mistook you for another,
but I cannot decide alone..
...what to do with you.
- But why?
This country is large
and I have no power!
I will hold a meeting and we will decide.
Until then, please,
wait here!
Prince Amesisis...
Come on, wake up!
Wake up, I said! Wake up!
Wake up! Wake up! Wake
up! Wake up! Wake up!
Listen, boy, is your parrot
good at imitating people?
I can imitate anyone from any country!
- Are you able to fly?
- I have flown all over the world!
Don't believe him!
But he really can fly!
What a fine friend! You meanie, you're
making me out to be a liar to everyone!
Please, fly to my country!
Tell a boy named Tink
to come help Sapphire!
- It's very easy!
- I'll reward you later!
- Alright! Where is your country?
- It's to the North!
Go, fly to the North!
Go call Tink, understood?
Away, to the North!
Nine more girls!
I will be buried alive with them!
Prince! Prince Amesisis!
I can't go back!
Prince!
Prince, what will become of me?
You will be a sacrificial victim,
it's already been decided!
Oh..! Oh, no!
Since we cannot manage to bring back
the girl who escaped to your country,
you must replace her
and sacrifice yourself in her place.
We will prepare a
very honorable sacrificial ceremony.
You will be offered
to the late Queen Deida.
It is said that Deida
was the second woman...
...most beautiful in the world,
after Cleopatra.
She is dead and now lies
more beautiful than ever in the pyramid.
But the youth and beauty
of the Queen will fade forever,
if every year there are not
offered as sacrificial victims...
...the ten most beautiful maidens
of the country.
And you have ten poor girls killed just because you believe...
- ...in a stupid superstition?
- A superstition?!
Prince, do you also believe this implausible story?
I believe it because Morufo believes it and assures me that it is the truth.
I never tell lies! It is necessary to offer sacrificial victims.
If we do not offer these victims, your late mother will be destroyed
..and Osiris will punish Egypt!
- It's a lie, Prince!
- Enough!
- I have nothing more to say!
You and the other nine girls
will all be sacrificed in five days.
Until then, enjoy yourselves
as much as you can.
I will not die!
Tink, what are you doing?
But why is none of you
crying or trying to escape?
I was chosen because I am beautiful.
But were you perhaps
born to be buried alive?
Listen, let's escape somehow.
I'm sure we will manage to
save ourselves if we run away.
- Sapphire!
- Tink!
Are you Tink?
Prince Amesisis...
- There is only one
way to save you - How?
It is to marry me! If you
marry me, you will not die!
Please, marry me! I
like you very much!
And I can make you truly happy!
Choose another girl.
I do not want to be saved
myself and let nine other girls die.
You can still live for three days,
you know. I await your answer.
Tink, where are you?
Oh, beautiful girls, this is
a night of the full moon.
Osiris...
Please, receive these
sacrificial victims...
...and please, offer youth
and beauty to Queen Deida.
May Queen Deida be young!
May Queen Deida be beautiful!
Enough! No matter how much
you pray, the dead can never again...
...return to being young and beautiful!
- Fear the wrath of Osiris!
A dead woman does not bloom again!
Have you gone mad from the
fear of becoming a sacrificial victim?
Lead the victims to the pyramid
where Queen Deida is sleeping!
Sapphire! Sapphire,
please, grant my request!
Marry me now or it will be too late!
No!
Sapphire!
Tink, is that you?
Tink, where are you?
Sapphire, I'm asking you
for the last time: marry me!
Otherwise it will be too late!
- Prince Amesisis...
I don't want you to
die, Sapphire! Marry me!
Even if you repeat it to
me endlessly, I won't do it!
I am not so petty as to save
myself by letting the other girls die.
If I did that,
it would be over for me.
- Sapphire!
- Tink, I'm here!
- What is it?
- Sapphire! - Sapphire!
Get them!
Oh, my God!
Help! Help!
Help!
Tink!
Sapphire, how cowardly I
am! I don't have the courage...
...to go against Morufo
and Osiris and save you.
Please, don't die!
Be careful not to step
on that black stone!
I warned you,
stupid boy.
In this pyramid there are
many traps to avoid thieves.
Osiris, please, receive
these sacrificial victims.
Goodbye forever!
That will be your coffin!
Great Osiris, please help
us, I don't want to die!
Try to take courage.
- Please, help us!
- Calm down and take courage.
I am certain there is
a secret hole to escape.
I am sure of it, because the pyramid
has many secret passages.
I'm tired! I'm tired!
Hel... Help!
Help! Help!
A crocodile!
Help! Help! Help!
We are being attacked
from both sides!
Thank you very much.
You saved our lives.
Thank you!
I'll be able to sell this boy well.
He can be sold for about 300 Yen.
Boss, it's a real fortune!
- But what are you talking about?
- We are slave traders.
You can be sold for 300 Yen.
Don't you think that's a good price?
You want to sell me?
No! No! No! No!
No! No! No! No! No!
I have to help Sapphire!
Let me go!
I really can't stay with you!
Look, are you going to put me down,
yes or no?
There is no hole!
I would have sworn there
had to be one.
Leave it alone, we have no
choice but to resign ourselves!
Osiris, sacrifice, and this
sort of thing are superstitions.
When you die you can no
longer become beautiful again!
Don't say those things! I am
afraid of Osiris's punishment!
And I am telling you that
there can be no punishment!
The mummy!
There is a secret door! Hurry
up! Quickly, let's escape from here!
Come!
Come, quickly! Here is the exit!
Oh...! Morufo!
Slave merchant,
this time these girls...
..they have given me a lot of trouble
because of this girl.
Slave merchant?!
It seems to me that this year the girls
are quite beautiful, right?
- You will pay a good price.
- All right. - I understand, Morufo!
Every year
you choose beautiful girls,
saying that you offer them
as sacrificial victims..
...and instead you sell them
to a slave merchant!
Isn't it a good trick
to say that I kill them...
..to protect
the Queen's beauty.
..and to appease the wrath of Osiris?
- Tie up the slaves!
- Let me go!
Damn! Did they really have to
shut me in a jar full of pepper?
Sapphire!
If they found me now I could no longer
save Sapphire! What can I do?
I've got it!
Father in heaven,
please forgive me,
but I'll have to make
the camels eat some pepper.
I'm sorry, camels
What's happening?
Tink, you've finally arrived!
Forward, Morufo!
Forward...
Wait!
Here I am, Morufo!
Morufo! Leave her alone
and fight against me!
Thank you, Sapphire. Now
I am strong because of you!
I will try to make my country
a country as good as yours.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Sen'nen man'nen hyakuman-nen
A thousand years, ten thousand years, a million years,
Ribbon de tsunagou ichioku-nen
Let’s connect with ribbons for a billion years!
Akuma ga kute mo arashi ga kute mo
Even if devils come, even if storms arrive,
tsunaida kokoro wa hanarenai
Our bonded hearts will never part.
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Tarari Ratta Ritta Ratta Rattattaa
Kyahoo! Kyahoo! Kyahoo!
Yahoo! Yahoo! Yahoo!
Subtitled by
SilverlandSubs
tinyurl.com/SilverlandSubs
Opening & Ending Song Lyrics Translation by
Natalia Arlovskaya
lyricstranslate.com/en/
translator/natalia-arlovskaya
EAN-13 : 8-031179-423880
ASIN : ‎ B0DQ54LVY1
EAN-13 : 8-031179-426225
ASIN : ‎ B0F1V5YTQP